我们最喜欢的宠物是这世界上最神奇的动物之一
Our favourite pets are among the most amazing animals on Earth
翻译：C大  B世界
它们已经成为我们家庭的一员和我们最好的伴侣
They've taken to a domestic life and become our perfect companions
但他们依旧保留着它们的天性
But their natural instincts remain intact
精校：C大
它们也许被驯服了几千年...
They may have been tamed for thousands of years...
时间轴：Red Bee Media  MVGroup
...但他们的野性却存在了上百万年
...but they were wild animals for millions more
特效：C大
@CharlesYF 译制
一些是聪明、优秀的捕食者
Some were smart and supreme predators
另一些则是捕食者的猎物
Others were alert and fleet-footed prey.
不论它们原来是什么，它们现在都和我们愉快的生活在一起
Whatever their origins, they now live happily among us
但它们最熟悉的行为是在野外形成的
But behaviour that feels familiar was born in the wild
仔细观察观察那些离狂野自然只有一翅之遥的生物们
Take a closer look, and discover the true animal sharing your home
去探索它们的本真
A creature just a wing-beat from the wild
宠物
内心狂野
我们自以为了解宠物
We think we understand our pets
萌萌哒还讨人喜欢
Cute and adored,
它们看起来一点也不像它们的那些野生的亲缘
they seem far removed from their wild living relatives
我们喜欢看它们玩耍
We love to watch them play
宠物的游戏
但在它们的眼里，这远远不只是玩耍
But there's more to their games than meets the eye
这些小萌货也在为今后成为优秀的捕食者而训练着
These puppies are still training for life as a predator
它们在游戏中熟悉群体中的捕猎规则
As they play, they rehearse the same rules
使它们的狩猎变得更有组织性
that enable wolves to hunt as an organised pack
他们必须时刻谨慎-即使只有七周大
They must take care - even at seven weeks,
也已经长满了28颗锋利的牙齿
these cockerpoos are armed with 28 needle-sharp teeth
占主导地位的小狗总是选择弱小的欺负，但它们都不会受伤
Dominant puppies choose to fight weaker ones, but no-one gets hurt
而那些不遵守规则的小淘气会被踢出圈子
Puppies that ignore the rules are soon ostracised by the others
它们必须学会如何控制咬合的力量
They must learn to restrain their bite
如果小狗露出了它最脆弱的腹部
If a puppy shows its vulnerable belly,
就说明它不要跟你玩惹
then it's a signal to take time out
或者说是打成平手-趁机开始练习当一个安静的"枕头杀手"
All else is fair game - a chance to let rip and practice killer holds
就没消停过
And death shakes too
它们需要通过团队合作来打败大型猎物
They need teamwork to bring down large prey,
即使现在，它们只是可怜的枕头君= =
even if, for now, it's just a cushion
尽管它们已经被驯养了30000多年
They may have been domesticated for 30,000 years,
但这些游戏还是为它们在野外生存做好了准备
but play still prepares them for life in the wild
然而这些游戏也有现代版的
But their games have modern relevance too
「啊呜~~~~~~」
HOWLING
狗狗比其他任何动物都更需要我们的陪伴
Dogs, more than any of our pets, must learn to rub along together
它们通常比任何的野生动物更能忍受这种状况
They're often forced into situations no wild animal would tolerate
在纽约，许多遛狗人都会一次带一群不同品种的狗狗出门锻炼
In New York, dog walkers exercise many different breeds at a time
这样更接近狗狗的真实生活
It's the closest the dogs get to pack life
但是和"枕头杀手"完全不同的是，这些狗狗从来都自顾自
But, unlike hunting wolves, these dogs are completely unrelated
最近纽约犬类主题公园的一项研究
Recent research in a New York dog park
揭示了狗狗社交的复杂性
revealed the full complexity of their social interactions
它们首先用它们引以为豪的嗅觉叙叙旧-
They first become reacquainted using their celebrated sense of smell -
它们的嗅觉比人类敏感100000倍
up to 100,000 times more sensitive than our own
嗅嗅别的狗狗的PP~（真的不明白为什么...）
By sniffing scent glands on another dog's bottom,
它们确认彼此身份
they check its identity,
以及饮食、健康状况和情感阶段
as well as its diet, health and emotional state
当每个成员都互相熟悉了之后，游戏就开始了
Once everyone's formally introduced, the play begins
它们玩的很疯
It may be boisterous,
但它们小时候的经验可以保证妈妈再也不用担心他们会受伤
but the wild rules they practised as pups
它们在事情失控之前就会停下来
stop things getting out of hand
撤退当然可以接受
Opting out is perfectly acceptable,
但对于小型犬来说就显得非常不讲道理
and for small dogs, not unreasonable!
萌萌哒小公主们肯定会觉得形式相当不利
Toy breeds must feel at a distinct disadvantage
而这只波士顿犬却选择挑战
But this Boston terrier's up for the challenge,
不管对手有多神
no matter how great!
但它知道规则
He knows the rules
点个头鞠个躬，我们都是好朋友
Exchange doggy bows, and he won't get hurt
这个"友好的仪式"
The "play bow" lets him have fun
让它和一个体型是它三倍的狗狗愉快的玩耍
with a Great Dane three times his size
这是每只狗狗都懂的一种邀请
It's an invitation every dog understands
当然也可以拒绝
It's quite OK to refuse, and anyway,
因为总能找到愿意玩耍的小伙伴
there are always others up for a game
通过一起跳跃以此来确定谁是最大的一个
Leaping together establishes who's biggest
这也是一种测试彼此的方式
It's another way to test each other
但是体型又不代表一切-
But, size isn't everything -
自信和姿势也很重要
it's about confidence and posturing too,
对于一只好战的英国斗牛犬
as this belligerent bulldog knows
这只年轻的拉布拉多展开四肢滚来滚去的玩耍-
The young Labrador uses a trick she learnt in play -
露出了他最脆弱的腹部
rolling over and exposing her vulnerable belly
斗牛犬好像在进攻中兴奋起来
The bulldog may be pumped up with aggression,
但拉布拉多的示弱让这场打闹就此结束
but the Lab's submissive posture takes the fight right out of him
和小伙伴们一起玩耍
Playing together as puppies
可以让狗狗明白公园里的规矩
allows dogs to understand the rules of the park
那些曾经是猎物的宠物们，玩的却是另一种游戏
Pets that are prey play different games
对于俄罗斯仓鼠来说，逃跑就是它们游戏的全部
For Russian hamsters, it's all about running
在自然界，它们一月之间可以跑出6公里
In nature, they cover six miles a night,
而它们也不得不比捕食者跑得更快
and they often have to outrun predators
而那些被我们当宠物圈养的小仓鼠
In captivity,
它们可以在小轮上跑出同样的速度
they can cover the same distance by running on the spot
看的出来它们玩得很嗨皮
And it seems they do it for fun!
科学家们在野外安放了同样的小轮
When scientists placed a wheel in the wild,
野耗子也跟家养小仓鼠一样没心没肺地玩了起来
mice took to it just as keenly as this enthusiastic hamster
就像人类的运动员一样，这种锻炼会产生大量的内啡肽
Like human athletes, exercise creates a rush of endorphins
这种物质能让小鼠越跑越欢乐
He experiences a runner's high
仓鼠如果全速冲刺，每分钟能迈出600步-
At full pelt he reaches 600 strides a minute -
是最快的赛马的4倍多
four times more than the fastest racehorse
从X光片可以看出，与马完全不同的是
Moving X-ray shows that, unlike horses,
不论它们跑的多快，也总有一只脚在地上
even when flat out he always keeps one foot on the ground
它也许已经跑的很快了
He may be fast,
但是有竞争对手的话它们能跑的更撒泼（我在想能不能这样发电= =）
but nothing improves performance like a bit of competition
仓鼠并不是最具有社交精神的动物
Hamsters aren't the most sociable of creatures
它们甚至可以说是非常不合群（小婊砸打起来了）
It seems they're bad losers too
失败者会去寻找一些安慰品
（注意观察盆里的食物，我不会告诉你之后会发生什么的）
The loser settles for the consolation prize
胜利者就夺得了金牌
while the winner goes for gold
与野耗子一样，家养小耗子基本只在黎明或黄昏时候撒泼
Like wild hamsters, he mostly runs at dawn and dusk
当然它们心情好的时候
But, when the time is right,
可以疯的超神
enthusiasm can get the better of him
疯癫的天性是如此的根深蒂固，从未正常过（摔得不痛么）
His racing instinct is so engrained, little puts him off
曾经对于野耗子来说，速度就是生命，貌似现在只是一种游戏
The quest for speed, once vital for survival, has become a game
甚至被当成杂技表演
One that also tests his acrobatic skills
但是想要臻于完美却又异常艰难
But, perfection is so hard to achieve!
疯玩的时候时间往往过得飞快
Time flies when you're having fun!
当一只玩得失心疯的时候，另一只也正享受自己的美好时光
（它为什么一只鼠把满满一盆东西都吃完了？！）
And, while he's been enjoying himself, so has the other hamster!
幼猫也会运用游戏的方法来锻炼自己的野外生存技巧
Kittens also use play to practise their wild skills
在野外，它们通常都是孤独的猎人
In nature, they are solitary hunters,
它们的游戏也正教会了它们独立生活
and their games prepare them for a life alone
它们会很多duang duang duang的特技
They have some impressive abilities to perfect
它们的眼睛对于细微的运动异常敏感
Their eyes are already reacting to the slightest movement,
但它们的反应就比较感人
but their reflexes still need sharpening
腿部的肌肉经过锻炼后
Leg muscles must be exercised too
可以跳到自己身长7倍的高度
He'll soon jump seven times his height
小猫爪会随着捕捉猎物的动作而张开
Claws and paws expand as he practices grasping prey
空中转体180是它们的另一项特技
His other qualities include a spine that can twist 180 degrees,
这时候它们就用尾巴来保持平衡
and a tail that acts as a counterbalance
再加上内置的减震器（目测指的是脚上的肉垫之类的）
so he famously lands on his feet
最后完美着陆（难度系数10.0）
He even has built-in shock absorbers!
正是这些特技让非洲野猫在10000多年前
It was these skills that made wild African cats useful pest controllers
就被驯服为害虫克星（实在不明白有什么逻辑关系）
when they moved in with the first farmers 10,000 years ago
这么多年后的今天，这些依旧没有改变
After all these years, little has changed
这些两个月大的孟加拉幼猫
These two-month old Bengal kittens are still practising
还在为适应独立狩猎的生活而努力练习着
for a life as independent hunters
在野外环境中，三个月之后
In the wild, in another three months,
它们就能独立捕猎食物了
they would be killing their own food
这些小猫马上就会被分散到各个家庭中，开始它们的新生活
These kittens will soon be separated and begin life in their new homes
但是无论它们的新主人是谁
But, whoever's pet they become,
它们都已经成为了一个出色的捕食者
they'll already be fully trained as a predator
这些无周大的垂耳兔，典型的被捕食者
Prey animals, like these five-week-old lop-eared rabbits,
也需要通过玩耍来学习生存之道
also practice their survival skills through play
对于这些蠢萌的生物来说，玩耍就是跳来跳去
For a rabbit, it's all about hopping!
这些跳跃也许是出于防御，但还是非常有趣
These leaps may be defensive, but learning is clearly great fun
它们的第六感告诉它们
Their mother's natural instincts
打洞是躲避天敌最好的方法
compel her to dig a bolt hole in case of predators
一些家养的兔子也有机会在野外进行这项游戏
Some pet rabbits get the chance to test out these games in the wild
为了找到它们，我们就得进入"兔子的地下世界"
To find them, we must go "down the rabbit hole" into another world
这个兔子天堂就坐落在日本的一个小岛上
This rabbit wonderland is on an island in Japan
这里甚至有一些大白兔（不要自动带入奶糖）
It even has a white rabbit,
它们是40年前宠物兔的后代
a descendant of pet rabbits released here 40 years ago
它们有很多颜色
They still come in many colours,
不过大多数的都是棕色
though most have reverted to the brown wild form
由于它们繁殖的...好吧，就像兔子一样快，现在岛上已经有几百只兔子了
Because they breed like, well, like rabbits, there are hundreds of them
虽然它们可以自由撒泼
They are free to express their wild instincts,
但它们在游客面前
but they have stayed tame,
还是乖的像宠物兔一样
and are treated like pets by adoring visitors
灵活运用这个原本是用来发现捕食者的技巧
By adapting a pose they use to spot predators,
它们甚至学会了恳求
they've even learnt to beg
但是那些相当傲娇的野兔们，从来不会像这样满足地站成一堆
But no self-respecting wild rabbit would contemplate standing so close
当大多数兔纸都冲向游客的时候
While most rush to greet the visitors,
这只大白兔总是慢半拍
the white rabbit is always late
大白兔在亚洲文化里，总让人联想到月亮
White rabbits are legendary across Asia,
使它们的身份更具传奇色彩
and its image is thought to be found on the face of the moon
所以它们经常会受到优待
So he always gets special treatment
这些兔子可能表现的像宠物一样
The rabbits may act like pets,
但是它们的自然直觉也会重新展现
but their natural instincts have resurfaced
除了像野兔子一样住在兔子洞里一样
As well as living in a warren like wild rabbits,
它们还要承担放哨的任务
some take up sentry duty
它的耳朵可以转动，以确认来自各个方向的声音
Her ears turn independently to pinpoint any sounds
（这只是乌鸦叫的声音而已...）
CROW CAWS
并且它的眼睛可以看到接近360度的全部景象
And she has eyes that can scan nearly 360 degrees
正在享受美食的兔子们要靠哨兵来发现危险情况
Grazing rabbits rely on sentries to warn them of danger
警报一旦发出，所有成员就都明白了
The alarm, when it comes, is understood by all...
...额...几乎所有成员（这么呆萌的除外）
..or nearly all!
在这时，逃生洞派上了大用场
Here, bolt holes are used in earnest
但是这只更加老练、睿智的兔子，懂的无视错误报警
（为什么我还是觉得真正的原因还是它比较呆萌）
But this older and wiser rabbit knows to ignore false alarms
这里从没发现过狐狸或老鹰
Foxes or eagles aren't found here,
而乌鸦只是打酱油的
and a crow is hardly in their league
当警报解除，兔子们又一如既往的卖起了萌
As life returns to normal, the rabbits do what they do best
但这种跳跃其实是很严肃的
But this is serious leaping
它们的后腿是它们最有价值的财产
Their back legs are their greatest asset,
能够帮助它们反击强大的对手
and a target for aggressive rivals
当它们跳起来的时候，这一踢同时也是一记防御性暴击
As they jump away, their kick packs a defensive punch
雌兔通过跳跃来躲避过于热情的雄兔
Females leap to ward off over-amorous males
雄兔通过比谁跳得高来确认谁是老大
And bucks compete in the high jump to prove who's best
在兔岛上，小兔子们放荡不羁
On Rabbit Island, the lessons learnt as playful youngsters
展现着它们的真正价值
show their true value
不论是什么宠物，与妈妈在一起的那些时光
For all our pets, the time spent with their mother
永远都是那么的重要
is the most important of their lives
这是在人类进入它们生活之前最好的培养野性一面的方式
It's an opportunity to nurture their wilder side before humans intervene
小猫，学着辨别自己的气味
Kittens learn to use a designated nipple
来找到专属于它的乳头
that they mark with their own distinct scent
这样就能把抢食的可能性
In this way, they keep squabbling to a minimum
降到最低
and themselves to themselves
它们可能已经展现出那么一点点独立的迹象
They may be showing the first signs of independence,
但它们毕竟还小，有困难找妈妈这点依旧不会变
but at this age, they depend on their mother for everything
热红外图像表明
Thermal imagery shows that even her body warmth
猫妈妈的体温对小猫的生存也极其重要
is vital for their survival
出生才10天的小猫不能很好的保持自己的体温
10-day old kittens can't regulate their temperature,
所以猫妈妈让它们尽量地靠近自己的皮毛
so she keeps them nestled in her fur
不经意间，一只小猫开始跑偏
Unseen, a kitten starts to stray
尽管它们的眼睛已经可以睁开了，但还是看不清东西
Although his eyes have only just opened, he still can't see clearly
远离了猫妈妈，它的热量也逐渐散失
And away from his mother, he's already losing heat
喵喵~~
KITTEN MEWS
它只能靠直觉叫喊
His instinct is to cry
没有一个母亲会忽视这种信号
And it's a call no mother can ignore
把小猫的后颈提起
Being carried by the scruff
让小猫本能的停止哭喊挣扎
triggers an instinct that stops him struggling,
或者发出一些吸引其他捕食者的声音
or making a sound that could attract predators
有幼猫的猫妈妈
A mother with young kittens
都会使用这个小技巧
instinctively uses this technique whenever she changes dens
搬家是个大事情，而找到充足的食物也很重要
Moving home is one thing, getting enough to eat is quite another
它住在日本的猫岛上，一个充满了流浪猫、被称为"猫的天堂"的地方
She lives on Cat Island in Japan, a moggie paradise full of feral cats
当时岛屿是一个桑蚕产业中心
They were imported to catch vermin
所以当时它们只是被用来抓害虫的
when the island was a centre for the silkworm industry
现在它们存活了下来
They now survive by scavenging from fishermen
靠捡拾渔民的废弃物为生
Their kittens are brought up in the perfect playground
但是繁忙的猫妈妈还是需要寻找足够的食物
But their busy mums have to juggle childcare
来喂饱它的孩子们
with the important job of getting a meal,
装满鲜鱼的渔船渐渐返航
and their chance comes just once a day
这种机会一天只有一次
The boats are returning, laden with fish
几周大的小猫非常喜欢独处
Kittens more than a few weeks old can happily be left alone
即使它们的母亲出去觅食
They are old enough to stay warm and keep out of trouble
这般大小的猫咪已经能够保持自己的体温了
as their mother searches for a meal
但猫妈妈总是有新的问题出现
But the mother with the new kitten faces a problem
10天大的小猫还不能自己呆着
At 10 days old, he's too young to be left on his own
所以当别的猫在享受全鱼宴的时候
So, mum's left holding the baby
它不得不留下来陪着自己的孩子
while the other cats enjoy their fish supper
争抢食物不可避免
Squabbles over food are inevitable
但是很快，每只猫都会分到一杯羹
But soon, everyone gets a slice of the action,
除了这只伟大的母亲
except for the new, and now very hungry, mother
它必须寻找其他的方法得到食物
She looks for a possible solution
它眯着它的眼睛-这是大部分猫都能明白的一种打招呼方式
She squeezes her eyes - a greeting that most cat owners will recognise
刚来的这位也向小猫问好
The new arrival grooms the baby...
然后它注意到了这位母亲
..then turns her attention to the mother
母猫希望它能帮着照看自己的孩子
It's her way of offering to babysit
在得到确认之前就马上离开了以防对方改变主意
The mother doesn't wait to see if she'll change her mind!
像这样的保姆猫其实很常见，尤其是有血缘关系的雌猫之间
Baby-sitting is natural among cats, especially between related females
这位就极有可能是母亲的姐妹
She's probably her sister
与此同时，猫妈妈正在搜索着其他猫剩下的残羹冷炙
Meanwhile, mum searches for scraps left by the other cats
对于保姆猫来说，这是一个很好的与小猫独处的机会
It's a chance for her childminder to enjoy time with the baby,
但是它貌似不是很懂应该做些什么
but she's clearly not sure what to do
小萌货激起了它的童心
The young kitten has reawakened her urge to play,
但显然游戏不太适合这么小的猫宝宝
even though he's far too young for games
这保姆简直就是一个噩梦...
（喂！你确定你是在帮姐妹照顾孩子？？！）
Then every baby-sitter's nightmare!
它瞄了几眼，附近貌似没有猫（难道你想畏罪潜逃？！）
She checks she hasn't been seen,
这蠢妈妈已经沉浸在美食中了...
but the mother's focused on gaining a meal
险境出奇迹，猪一样的队友也终究能想出个办法来
Desperate times call for desperate measures
妈妈终于感觉到有什么不对劲
The mother senses something's wrong
在千钧一发之际，bingo！
But then, in the nick of time, success!
下次猫妈妈也许会找个靠谱的保姆吧
Mum might try a less playful baby-sitter next time!
正是猫的这种玩性
It's the cat's playful nature,
还有它们独立的性格
as well as their independence of mind, that helps make them
打败了蠢萌的狗狗
the world's most popular pet,
成了世界上最受欢迎的宠物
beating dogs, paws down
居于第三位的宠物，也是非常爱玩
Our third most cherished pet is equally playful
最常见的鹦鹉，或者称之为虎皮鹦鹉
The common parakeet, better known as the budgerigar,
在澳大利亚的内陆地区被发现
is found naturally in the outback of Australia.
这种群居动物
They are social birds,
在觅食和饮水的时候总喜欢成群结队
occurring in huge flocks as they search for both food and water
它们是当之无愧的高智商
They are highly intelligent
在这么庞大的队伍之中，它们也不可能与家人走散
and, even in the heart of the flock,families stick together
鹦鹉的这种友好的性格，让它们在过去的150年间
It's this friendly nature that, for the last 150 years,
成为了人类最好的朋友
has made them such perfect human companions
在家里，这些天生没办法静下来的群居鸟
In homes, these intensely social birds
总能想方设法的给自己找到玩伴
are hard-wired to seek out company
[鹦鹉叽叽喳喳，自言自语]
BIRD TWEETS AND CHATTERS
「魔镜魔镜，快快显灵，告诉我谁才是这世界上最漂亮的鸟儿？」
Who's a pretty bird? Disco, who's a pretty bird? Baby
镜子可以让鹦鹉暂时忘却孤独
A mirror provides a temporary companion -
它当然不会知道
he doesn't see it as a reflection of himself,
它一直在和自己么么哒
more a buddy who comes and goes
但当问问魔镜谁是最漂亮的鸟儿已经不能满足它的时候
But, when he wants some real quality time,
它总会想出点小把戏来吸引人的注意力
he's learnt some playful tricks to get noticed
「不陪我玩就捣蛋~~
BIRD WHISTLES
「看我打翻你的碗
CUP RATTLES
「踢飞你的球」
BALL CRASHES TO THE FLOOR
「嗨嗨嗨，小婊砸
I see you over there! Baby bird, baby bird
你给我过来
Come on, baby bird!
看看你干的好事，Disco！妈妈是怎么教你的？
What are you doing, Disco? What did mama say?
你在跳迪士科么？
Are you dancing? What is it, Disco?
小婊砸快过来
Yah? Come on over
到妈妈这儿来」
Come on out
吸引到它主人的注意力后
Having captured his owner's attention,
它还有更多把戏可以玩
he can practice another skill
「当个绿婊砸不容易吧」
It's not easy being green
「当个绿婊砸不容易吧，当个绿婊砸不容易吧」
BIRD: It's not easy being green. It's not easy being green
鹦鹉学舌并不像它看上去那样是天生的
Mimicry isn't as unnatural as it seems
野生鹦鹉互相学舌
Wild parakeets mimic each other,
不同的家族就有不同的口音
and each family learns their own distinct calls
「从没见过小鹦鹉
Never shake a baby bird
那一定非常奇怪
That would surely be absurd
从没见过小鹦鹉
Never shake a baby bird
那一定非常奇怪」
That would surely be absurd
这只鸟所做的和它在群鸟中做的是一样的事
This budgie is just doing what he would do in the flock
「0101，我是鹦鹉，你是什么鬼？
Is that a parakeet. What is it?
一个绿绿黄黄的小婊砸？
A green and yellow bird that talks?
其实这不重要
That's not important right now
有个名字其实并没有看上去这么糟
Even having a name may not be as unnatural as it seems
我知道我叫Disco！
I'm Disco and I know it
我不是骗子，你才是骗子，你全家都是骗子！我就叫Disco！」
I am not a crook. My name is Disco
野生鹦鹉父母当孩子一出生就会给它一个代号
Wild parrots have been shown to assign special calls
就像我们的名字一样，像我们给我们的宠物起名
to name their offspring, just as we name our own pet budgies
「亲爱的Disco
Baby bird. Disco baby bird
你的名字是Disco」
Keep it bird
因此，这些鹦鹉就学着使用它
In turn, young parrots learn these names
以此来介绍自己
and use them to introduce themselves
「我告诉过你我的名字是Disco」
I am not a crook. My name is Disco
这种非凡的能力也许预示着
This extraordinary ability may mean that Disco
Disco十分清楚自己的身份
has a sense of his own identity
它的表现正说明了这一点
It certainly seems so at times
「亲爱的Disco」
Disco baby
说话就像游戏一样
Talking is now a game,
能让鹦鹉在家中也展现出它野性的一面
a way to express wild behaviour in the confines of his home
「看那，来了一只猫，喵喵喵~」（它是一只狗啊...尊严呢...）
A cat. Meow, meow
「来来来，亲一个~」(猫狗都不分就调戏人家)
Give me a kiss
「我有你爱的芝士汉堡~」
I can has cheeseburger
「你是个矮子急先锋？」
Aren't you a little short for a stormtrooper?
「Disco~」
Disco
「我以前是间谍，现在是鹦鹉」
I used to be a spy, then a parakeet
「呸！我是医生，不是鹦鹉」
Phew, I'm a doctor, not a parakeet!
「蠢猫，懂了没，我是医生」
I'm a doctor
Disco大约能记130多个短语
Disco, has memorised over 130 phrases in all
「我的笼子里别有洞天」
My cage is bigger on the inside
就像学习一门外语那样，多多的练习能让它掌握得更好
Like learning any new language, practice makes perfect,
也许这就意味着它会在你睡觉的时候balabalabala个不停
even if it means talking in your sleep
「载我一程。跟上」
Give me free ride. Keep up
「我要免费的」
Give me for free
「谁想...」
Nobody expects...
「晚安Disco」
（我滴个亲娘...这话痨终于说完了，翻译这前言不搭后语的东西简直心力憔悴） Good night Disco
Disco和它主人亲密关系非比寻常
The intimacy between Disco and his owner may be unusual,
这也许正是因为这愉快的游戏
but the desire to play can bring the oddest of couples together
之前讲到过，狗狗在开始游戏前都会鞠个躬
The puppy uses play bows to start a game,
而一般来说喵星人根本不懂这一套
something a cat wouldn't normally understand
但是这只喵星人从小就和狗狗在一起
But, the cat has known the puppy since she was born,
自然也就明白这道理了
and he's learnt her playful signals
喵星人回敬一个礼，玩耍就这样开始了
Having agreed to a game, he keeps his claws firmly sheathed
猫和狗是最受我们人类欢迎的宠物之一
Cats and dogs are our most popular pets,
但是我们对待他们的态度截然不同
but we treat them both very differently
猫是唯一有完全出入自由的宠物
Cats are the only pets with the freedom
它们有大把大把的空闲时间
to come and go as they please
这只忍者神猫
With plenty of time to play with,
开始玩它自己的游戏
this ginger tom has created his own game
事实上它完全可以走大门...
He free climbs for fun
但它也许只想安静地做一只愉快的蜘蛛猫
He could have used the cat flap!
准备得越充足，它就能爬的越高
Impressive, but great feats require careful preparation
它把它的指甲磨尖
He scratches to make sure his claws are sharp
这样的动作可以使包裹爪子的指甲脱落
This removes old claw coverings, which break off and fall
新的更锋利的指甲就长在这旧壳下面
These sheaths protect the new sharp claw growing underneath
旧指甲每几周就掉一次
They are lost naturally every few weeks
因为安全是最重要的
But it's better to be safe
一个闪失就有可能导致摔得很惨
Climbing demands equipment that can be relied on
所以攀爬对于硬件的要求也是极高的
A loose sheath now could spell disaster
当游戏变得更富有挑战性的时候，它还有一个隐藏技能
When the climb gets challenging, he has a hidden tool
这是金克拉
It flicks out like a knife
萌萌的金克拉（听说最近金克拉很火）
This is the dewclaw -
野生猫就是通过利用这副爪来爬树捕猎
（不闹了，上面说的金克拉其实是副爪= =）
a claw wild cats use to climb trees while chasing prey
这把利刃就是这只忍者神猫的秘密武器
This tom needs all the help he can get
这局面简直就是绝岭雄风
This is what's commonly called a cliff-hanger
或者说是劫后余生
Another sheath falls - a close shave
这是它所有的生存技能，它成功了！
With all his proverbial lives intact, he survives another day
而那只黑猫只是无聊的发霉想找点事做做而已
The black cat was simply expressing his irrepressible urge to play
与之相反
In contrast, playtime for dogs
狗狗往往是主人的好帮手
is usually at the hands of their owners
但在狗狗的世界里，被带出来散步，是很不同的体验
But in her doggy world, being taken for a walk is seen very differently
对它来说，这其实就好像一场想象中的狩猎
For her, it's an imaginary hunt
利用它灵敏的嗅觉
She searches for scent trails,
来规划它的狩猎路线
zigzagging her nose to stay on track
它能嗅出谁在什么时候来过这里
She's aware of who passed and when,
甚至能追溯到好几周前
even getting information from trails left several weeks ago
它调动起它的十二分警觉
She's hypersensitive to every sound and movement,
希望能发现什么
hoping for something to chase
扔一个球，会让它想象出猎物逃走的画面
Throw a ball and she's mentally back pursuing prey
然后就利用它完美的狩猎天赋重新把猎物抓回来
And she catches it with instinctive precision
狗狗是一种坚定的动物
With the determination of a wild animal,
它时刻都准备着，跑！
she's always ready to run again
在玩耍的时候，健康的狗狗会不同的奔跑
In play, fit dogs will run and run
它们是天生的马拉松健将
Their wild relatives are champion marathon runners,
通过不懈的追逐来耗尽猎物的体力
exhausting their prey by chasing them down
像狼一样，这只德国牧羊犬的时速可达35迈（约合56km/h）
Like a wolf, this German shepherd can reach 35mph,
而且它们一天里可以愉快的跑上50多里
and can happily cover 50 miles in a day
覆盖与全身的毛发
Blanketed with fur from head to paws,
完美得隔绝了严寒
he's perfectly insulated against the cold,
但真的好热的时候
but, when things really hot up,
它就只能从脚掌排汗了
he can only sweat through his foot pads
其实它还可以利用舌头来散热
Instead, he uses his tongue to lose heat by evaporation -
当血管扩张的时候
as its blood vessels dilate,
舌头就会伸出来开始排汗
the tongue extends and swells
不停的喘气加速血液的冷却
Panting cools the hot blood even faster
红外成像显示了狗狗主要的散热部位
Thermal imagery shows where all the heat escapes,
在毛发最浓密的部位几乎没有热量散失
and how no heat is lost through his thick coat of fur
有这么一只为追逐猎物而生的宠物
With a pet so geared for a life chasing prey,
有时候难以管教也就不足为奇了
it's hardly surprising they're sometimes so difficult to control
让这只已经玩脱了的狗狗
Let a dog off the leash
以及他的惊人天赋乱入一下
and her natural instincts kick in
它总是做一些疯狂到让人想不到的事情
She's always on the edge of doing something wild and unexpected
这只玩high的狗狗一次又一次的跳入水中
This playful dog takes the plunge again and again
这个曾经对它的生存至关重要的技能
She may enjoy her mischievous game,
现在只是它欢乐的游戏而已
but once it had real survival value
狼仍旧用狗刨式过河来追捕猎物
Wolves still often use doggy paddle to cross rivers in pursuit of prey
狗狗在游泳的时候也就像在岸上小跑那样
When a dog swims, he simply trots as he would on land,
只不过把腿伸得更长动得更快而已
but makes longer and faster strides
这只high翻了的牧羊犬
This bearded collie
完美的诠释了这种划水动作的高效
shows how surprisingly effective this stroke is
为了尽可能地提高效率，它在划水的时候会张开脚掌
For maximum efficiency, she spreads her paws on the downstroke
狗狗在水中，视力照样惊人得好
Dogs see surprisingly well under water, too
如狗刨式这样的一些娴熟的技能
As they doggy paddle, they practise skills
使它们的祖先
that helped their ancestors become the most widespread
成为远古捕食者中分布最广的宠物
of all predators
狗狗很不寻常的获得了这样的自由
Dogs are unusual in having such freedom
但大多数的宠物只能像这样
Most pets have to fulfil their natural urges
在笼子里度过一生
within the confines of their cage
萌萌哒金丝熊
All pet golden hamsters
是上个世纪中期
are descended from just one family
在叙利亚的沙漠中
found in the deserts of Syria
被发现的一个仓鼠家族的后裔
in the middle of the last century
我们给他们设置了管道系统
Give them a tunnel system,
以此来模拟
and they are transported
野生的环境
back to the wild
白天，它们藏在沙漠的洞穴里
In the desert, they would shelter from the heat and predators
躲避酷暑和捕食者
by hiding in burrows during the day
透过X-光我们可以发现它是有多么的灵活
Moving X-rays reveal just how manoeuvrable he is
它灵活的脊椎让它们使这种急转弯成为可能
His flexible spine allows him to take sharp turns easily
事实上，它灵活的脊柱甚至可以允许它原地转身
In fact, his spine is so bendy, he can completely turn back on himself
几乎没有其他的动物可以做到
Few other animals can perform this complete U-turn
发现食物后
Presented with food,
它表现得好像每次都是最后一餐一样
he acts as if it's his last meal,
它把食物尽可能多的塞进颊囊里以待日后享用
stuffing the surplus into cheek pouches to be eaten later
为了能够保持食物的干燥
To keep his food fresh and dry,
这时候它不会分泌唾液
he secretes no saliva
X-光告诉我们它到底是如何做到把这么多食物都塞进嘴里的
X-ray shows just how he packs it all in
它的食袋能一直撑大到臀部
（吃货一定表示不服，也想要这个特技）
His pouches extend all the way to his hips
看来是实在塞不下了
And when he can't fit in another morsel,
但它还是决定干脆一路叼回去
he carries his favourite treat with him
当然说起容易做来难
Easier said than done!
成功送到目的地后，如何把食物重新吐出来又是一大挑战
Disgorging his stash is his next challenge
坚果有可能会卡在他干燥的颊囊里
The nuts stick to his dry cheek pouches
但聪明的金丝熊总有解决的办法
But he has a way to tackle the problem -
它有异常灵活的小萌爪
his surprisingly dexterous paws
仓鼠拼命的储存食物
Hamsters make these stores, because in the desert
只是因为在荒漠里基本上都是吃了上顿没下顿的
they never know where their next meal may come from
当然-在这里，这只能说是一种忆苦思甜
Here it's a form of play - a way to enjoy wild behaviour
全当消遣的游戏
that in captivity has no real purpose
即使是一直拥有完全的自由的宠物
Even a pet that has all the freedom in the world,
比如这只伯曼猫
like this Birman cat,
依旧花费大把的时间
still spends most of her waking hours hunting
在没有实际目的的捕猎上
for no useful reason at all
捕猎的欲望也许无法抑制
The urge to hunt may be irresistible
但是它从来不会挨饿
but as she's never hungry
所以完全没有必要杀掉这只田鼠
there's no point killing the vole
把田鼠带回家
It's far more fun to release it
比直接杀了它要有趣的多
in the confines of her home
捕猎已经不再那么必要
Hunting is no longer a necessity -
完完全全的变成了一种游戏
it too has become a game
重点不在于杀死猎物
The point isn't to kill her prey -
而是享受这种猎杀的过程
it's all about the chase
虽然有把耗子玩丢的风险...
Even at the risk of losing it completely
小耗子：「看我三十六计走为上」
VOLE SQUEAKS
心中默念：「你看不见我看不见我看不见我...」
这种猫鼠游戏
Such cat and mouse games
是这只无聊的喵星人用来消磨时间的最好办法
are the whole focus of her free time
它甚至会花费20多个小时
She spent over 20 hours hunting
只是为了抓住这只田鼠
just to get this vole
「我他喵的好不容易抓到你
Having invested so much time catching it,
怎么可以这样就放跑你！」
she's not about to let it go easily
但过不久
But then again,
它也很容易丧失专注力
it's so easy to lose concentration
「蠢猫拜拜啦~」
VOLE SQUEAKS
放跑小宠物也许很心塞
It may be frustrating,
但至少满足了它捕猎的欲望
but at least she's fulfilled her
（喂！你回来啊！家里的耗子你确定不管了？！今儿晚饭想不想要了？）
natural urge to hunt
家养的猫很少会吃掉它们杀死的猎物
Domestic cats rarely eat their kills,
主人为它们准备的食物已经足够它们享用
they have everything they need presented on a plate
猫与其他宠物不同
Cats are unusual among our pets
只要它们喜欢，它们可以随意进出人类的家
as they are free to come and go from our homes as they please
但是在秘鲁库斯科
But in Cusco in Peru,
狗狗也可以（随意进出）
pet dogs traditionally do the same
每天，它们从家里走出去，想干嘛干嘛
Each day they're let out from their house to do whatever they wish
「滚开！这是我的地盘！」
THEY BARK
为了揭秘它们的生活我们让其中一些带上了微型摄像机
To reveal their secret lives, some are carrying mini-cameras
似乎每只狗狗都有它们各自的使命
Each dog seems to be on its own individual mission
但在它们四处游荡的时候，就渐渐聚集到一块儿了
But as they travel, numbers build
幸运的是它们懂的红灯停绿灯行
Fortunately, they're streetwise and traffic savvy
「嘿，小心，看着路！」
CARS TOOTING
虽然有些事野狗，但大部分都有主人
Although some of these dogs are strays, most have owners,
它们就像当地司机那样对道路了如指掌
and all know the streets of Cusco as well as any local cab driver
它们不仅仅只有令人惊异的交通安全意识
They not only have a surprising grasp of road safety,
甚至还理解人类的礼仪文明
but they understand human etiquette, too
在经过人身边的时候它们也是排着队过
They're never aggressive to people
从来不攻击人类
and just step into line as they pass
它们看起来好像在向着同一个地点集合
They seem to be converging on the same spot
这是属于它们的城市，它们知道这城市的每个神秘角落
This is their city, and they know every secret gathering place
这只摄影狗很快入了伙—一个有着20只狗狗的大帮派
The camera-dog soon finds the gang - a huge pack of 20
「快快快，排队排队，不要挤，再挤就迟到了~」
DOGS BARK UP AHEAD
这比一般的狼群要大得多
This is far bigger than the average wolf pack,
而且和狼不同的是，它们之间没有任何亲缘关系
and, unlike wolves, these dogs are unrelated -
它们只是从城市的各个角落聚集起来的而已
they are just mutts from all over town
摄影狗走进看看
The camera-dog takes a closer look
注意力的焦点放到了这只发情的母狗身上了
The centre of attention is this female on heat
这种发情的气味将这些雄性从三里外甚至更远的地方吸引过来
The scent enticed the males from three miles away, or more
不过我们的摄影狗太冒失了
But the camera-dog is pushing his luck -
它看起来已经有伴了
she already has a partner
「小子看看清楚，不要命了？！」
VICIOUS SNARLING
很显然，它已经选择了一只有潜力的霸道总裁汪
She's chosen a dog with proven tough credentials
这只利齿的搏击手让其他的狗毫无胜算
This canine bruiser holds everyone else at bay
「从今天开始我就是你们的老大！」
SNARLING CONTINUES
现在，这些只是在玩耍的"愚蠢的"人类
It's only the people who are playing games, now -
对狗狗来说事态很严峻
for the dogs, things have just got serious
在越来越紧张的气氛中，大战一触即发
In frustration, fights break out
「来啊，你不是很能打么，我们练练！」
SNARLING AND BARKING
这时候这已经不再是纽约主题公园中的游戏
And this is no dog park,
这是街斗
this is real street-fighting
「老子今天就让你知道谁才是最强的！」
BARKING AND SNARLING
尽管看起来很凶残
But, despite the ferocity,
但他们在小时候就学会了控制局面的规则
the rules they learned as playful puppies govern the encounter -
很少发生真正的撕咬
the bites rarely make contact,
基本不会产生重伤
and no-one gets seriously hurt
所有的狗都从打斗中确立了统治地位
Through these fights, everyone gets to know who is top dog
它也许不是城里最英俊的杂种狗
He might not be the best-looking mutt in town,
但它最后还是获得了美女的芳心，抱得美人归
but he is the one who finally gets the girl
虽然是打斗让它们相识
Despite the aggression that got these new romantics together,
但它们之间却有着令人惊奇的柔情
there is surprising affection between them
关于这些狗，还有另外一件很特殊的事情
And there's something else very special about these dogs -
在太阳快要落山的时候
at the end of the day, it's their choice
他们准备回家
whether to go home
晚餐时间它们也都分道扬镳
As soon as it's dinner time, they start to peel away
有的结对而回
Some travel in groups...
其他的孑然独行
..and others travel alone
但是它们的心中都只有一个地方
But they've just one place in mind
在野性与舒适的家这两项选择之间-
In a choice between the wild and home comforts -
它们知道他们的忠诚所在
they know where their loyalties lie
是它们与我们之间的亲密友谊
It's their close companionship with us,
禁锢了它们心中的野性
that keeps the wild wolf at bay
库斯科狗也许公然的享受着双重的生活
Cusco dogs may openly lead a double life,
但其实所有的宠物都有接触它们狂野一面的方式
but all our pets find ways to get in touch with their wild side
即使只是通过玩耍
even if it's just through play
它们也许生活在我们身边
They may live among us
也许被我们照料，甚至崇拜
and be cared for and adored,
但是它们真正的野性
but their true wild nature
仅仅潜伏在咫尺之遥
is just a whisker away
好啦！
Hola!
下一次，我们会看到潜藏的感知和秘密的交流
Next time, we'll see how the hidden senses
是如何使我们的宠物
and secret communications of our pets
在心中保留着一份野性的
also keeps them wild at heart